We'll start with an example.
我们先来举个例子
Let's say we're in an office and there are two people,
假如我们在一个办公室里 办公室里有两个人 Alex 和 Brenda
Alex and Brenda, and they are both there the same amount of time.
他们在办公室的时间一样长
One day we're in the office and we see someone passing by really fast.
有一天 我们坐在办公室里 看见有人快速地走过
We can't tell who it is,
我们没有看清这个人到底是谁
but we'd like to take a guess.
我们先做个猜测
So far with all we know,
目前我们的全部信息是
all we can infer is that since they're both in the office the same amount of time,
Alex 和 Brenda 在办公室里的时间一样长
the probability of the person being Alex is
此人是 Alex 的概率为 50%
50% and the probability of the person being Brenda is also 50%.
此人是 Brenda 的概率也为 50%
But now let's try to use more information so
现在让我们尝试利用更多的信息
we can make a better guess of who the person is.
来猜猜此人是谁
When we saw the person running by,
当我们看见此人经过时
we noticed that they were wearing a red sweater,
我们留意到他身穿红色毛衣
so we'll use that piece of information.
因此我们要利用这一条信息
We've known Alex and Brenda for awhile,
我们已经认识 Alex 和 Brenda 一段时间了
and actually we've noticed that Alex wears a red sweater
我们注意到 Alex 一周穿两次红色毛衣
two days a week and Brenda wears a red sweater three days a week.
而 Brenda 一周穿三次红色毛衣
We don't know which days, but we are sure of this fact.
尽管我们不知道具体是哪天
Also when we say week, we mean work week,
我们这里的一周指工作日的五天
so five days, although at the end this won't matter much.
这点其实不是很重要
So, now what we'll do is we'll use
我们要做的就是利用这点信息
this piece of information to help us make a better guess.
来帮助我们进行更好的猜测
First off, since Alex wears a red sweater less than Brenda,
首先 因为 Alex 穿红色毛衣的次数少于 Brenda
it's easy to imagine that it's a bit less likely that
很容易想到此人是 Alex 的概率
the person we saw is Alex than that it is Brenda.
小于此人是 Brenda 的概率
But exactly how likely?
但概率具体小多少呢?
Well, let's say that if we saw a person pass by five times,
比如说我们有五次看到有人经过
it would make sense to think that two of these times it was
很容易想到此人是 Alex 的次数有两次
Alex since he wears a red sweater twice a week,
因为 Alex 一周有两次穿红色毛衣
and the other three times it was Brenda since she wears a red sweater three times a week.
而此人为 Brenda 的次数为三次  因为她一周有三次穿红色毛衣
Therefore, from here we can infer that the probabilities are 40 and 60.
因此 我们可以得到各自的概率为 40% 和 60%
We've used the information about the color of the sweater to obtain
我们利用了毛衣的颜色
better probabilities about who was the person who passed by.
得到了猜测过路人身份更准确的概率
This is Bayes Theorem and we'll learn it more in detail in the next few videos.
这称为贝叶斯定理 我们将在接下来的几个视频中进行详细学习
The initial guess we had, the 50-50 guess,
起初的猜测概率为 50% 50%
is called the prior since it's all we could
称为先验概率
infer prior to the new information about the red sweater.
因为这是我们在没有新信息红毛衣之前做出的推断
The final guess we have, the 60-40 guess,
而最后猜测的概率为 60% 40% 称为后验概率
is called the posterior since we've inferred it after the new information has arrived.
因为这是我们在得到红毛衣这条新消息之后做出的推断